Felipe Bascou

Frontend Software Developer

felipe_bascou@hotmail.com +90 534 268 87 95 Github_LinkedIn Highly motivated professional committed to pursuing a long-term frontend software development career. Offers 2 years as a frontend developer with experience in Javascript, Typescript, React, HTML, CSS, MySQL, and Python.

Technical Skills

Frontend Backend Tools Javascript Python3 Salesforce Typescript MySQL GIT ReactJS JIRA HTML AdobeXD CSS/SASS Figma

Languages

English (Native) Spanish (Native) French (Fluent) Chinese Mandarin

Education

Arden University

Berlin, Germany (04/2018 - 09/2019) MSc. Data Analysis & Marketing

Beijing Foreign Studies University Beijing, China (09/2011 - 07/2015) B. B. A. International Marketing

Volunteering

Beijing Foreign Studies University International Business School Union Beijing, China (2012 – 2013) Marketing Assistant Manager

Empowered Student Partnership Toronto, Canada (2007 – 2009) Volunteer

Legal Status

European Citizen
Willing to relocate

Work Experience

Born2Global Centre

Seoul, South Korea (04/2021 – 09/2022) Digital Transformation Manager

Digital Transformation Manager (01/2022 – 09/2022)

- Led and managed both the web development team and marketing team
- Frontend developer for the company's new website with *React, Typescript, SASS, Formik, Yup, and Axios*
- Created and managed a digital marketing campaign and strategy (surveys, customer buyer personas, content, data analysis & reports) with Facebook, LinkedIn, Youtube, and MailChimp campaign ads, as well as Google Analytics
- Automated tasks with *Python* using Google, Naver, and Salesforce *APIs*
- WordPress admin (created and managed posts, products, templates)

Global Business Alliance Manager (04/2021 – 12/2021)

- Organized and managed offline and online global events with Colombia, Chile, Argentina, South Korea, IDB, CABEI, and GIGF
- Conducted Deep Tech South Korean and Latin American Market reports and analysis
- Supported the creation of 5 JVs between South Korean and LATAM companies
- Salesforce admin (updated forms, connected Gmail with SF, created SF APIs)
- Automated tasks with *Python* and Google Sheets Macros (*Javascript/GoogleScript*)

Id For Ideas - Equipo78 Github

Community/Open-Source Project (01/2022 - Present)

Teamlead & Frontend Developer

- Create, manage, and admin the group with Discord, JIRA, and Github
- Develop frontend online-homebanking page with *React, Typescript, SASS, Redux Toolkit, Zod, and Axios*

Green Smart Tech Github

Freelance (07/2021 - 09/2021)

Frontend Developer

- Designed the client's website using AdobeXD
- Developed multi-paged and a form with *Javascript, PHP, HTML, CSS*, and HTTP requests for form handling

Client Portfolio Website Github

Freelance (01/2021)

Frontend Developer

- Designed the client's website using AdobeXD
- Developed with Javascript, HTML, and CSS